Hey everybody and welcome to the
content video going over section 3
.9 augmented assignment and this is
a pretty simple idea. It's mostly
it's mostly just a shortcut for
something that you probably already
know how to do and it's something
that goes right along with
loops. So what we're used to doing
is saying doing some math like this
total equals total plus one or
total equals total minus one plus
subtract so I just said the same
things twice I meant to say multiply
divide exponent whatever modulo
an augmented assignment is just
kind of simplifying that into a
statement called plus equals or minus
equals or mod equals and there's
a whole list of them right here
so plus equals minus equals multiply
equals I don't know if you guys
can see that maybe it's too small
exponent equals divide equals
floor divide equals modulo equals
and here's some examples of what
they would look like so rather than
waste time in the textbook because
it's a pretty short section we'll
just jump over into a couple
of examples um what is this called
sorry um augmented assignment um
okay so what this is gonna look
like is basically like let's
say we've got, oh I don't know,
age equals 90 and then what
we're used to doing is we're
used to saying age equals age
plus one, print out age, and
we all know what that should
give us, 91, there it is. So
what we're saying we can do now
we can do age plus equals one
and then let's print out age.
And what you would expect to see
is 92 because we already added
one to age. So I'm just gonna copy
this from my notes and show you
because it's a little bit easier
here than typing all this out.
Let's do age minus equals 11,
floor divide equals by two,
and multiply equals by 7.
Let's see what that gives us.
Okay,
so 91, 92, and then we minus
equals 11, so that gave us 81,
and then we floor divided that
by 2, which remember floor
division lops off the extra
decimals and remainder and whatnot,
so we get an even 40, and then
we times equal that by 7, which
7 times 4 is easy math, and
you just add 0 on the end, 28,
sorry not 2800,
280.
All right, Let's use a loop to
actually implement augmented
assignment. Let's say we've got a
list of grades. Oops, I'm not typing.
Let's say we've got a list of grades.
And you guys are all doing amazing
in the class, so we're going to use
your grades as an example. I'm just
kidding. I'm just making these up.
And what we want to do is
let's say we have a total.
and I want to add up all the grades using
a for loop. So I'll
say for grade in grades
and I will say total plus equals grade.
And then outside our loop,
let's print out what the
total grades are
total
total grades are 404 grade not found
right so this is awesome but this
is also great for calculating an
average right because now all we
have to do is divide that total by
the length of grades right and that's
a list thing so we'll not do it
like that but we'll say print out
average grade
is, and then we'll take total and
we'll divide it by 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
It's 80.8. So a really nice
and easy way to calculate an
average is using a loop and
augmented assignment, and then just
some basic arithmetic. So I
think that covers everything I
wanted to cover for this content
video, so thanks for watching.